<!-- This file was generated by the NWNTools GFF to XML writer.
     http://nwntools.sf.net/
     ** Do not hand edit unless you know what you are doing. **
 -->
<gff name="ahousedeed.uti" type="UTI " version="V3.2" >
    <struct id="-1" >
        <element name="TemplateResRef" type="11" value="ahousedeed" />
        <element name="BaseItem" type="5" value="29" />
        <element name="LocalizedName" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="A House Deed" />
        </element>
        <element name="Description" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="" />
        </element>
        <element name="DescIdentified" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" >
                <value><![CDATA[This is a house deed. It keeps track of the furniture in your house.

Players are allowed ONE house per character. There are three house sizes, small, medium, and large. House size determines the maximum number of furniture that you can have.

The type of key you have determines what size house you have access to. 

Once you enter a house, you can place furniture at the sparkling pillars. Just stand next to one, and use your furniture deed.

If you can't see any sparkling pillars, double click your house deed, and target an empty location on the floor.

If you wish to delete a piece of furniture you have placed, double click your deed, then the furniture that is to be destroyed. 
This will completely destroy the furniture, and no refund is given.

If you want to boot someone from your house, double click your key, then the player you want removed.

If you want to let other people into your house, you must enter it first, then unlock the front door with the lever. 
Don't forget to relock it! Houses only lock themselves if you physically leave the house.

Lastly and VERY IMPORTANT, do not place your deed in your bank chest - if you do not have your deed when entering your house you will lose all your furniture.]]></value>
            </localString>
        </element>
        <element name="Tag" type="10" value="empty" />
        <element name="Charges" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="Cost" type="4" value="3" />
        <element name="Stolen" type="0" value="1" />
        <element name="StackSize" type="2" value="1" />
        <element name="Plot" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="AddCost" type="4" value="0" />
        <element name="Identified" type="0" value="1" />
        <element name="Cursed" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="ModelPart1" type="0" value="33" />
        <element name="PropertiesList" type="15" >
            <struct id="0" >
                <element name="PropertyName" type="2" value="15" />
                <element name="Subtype" type="2" value="329" />
                <element name="CostTable" type="0" value="3" />
                <element name="CostValue" type="2" value="13" />
                <element name="Param1" type="0" value="255" />
                <element name="Param1Value" type="0" value="0" />
                <element name="ChanceAppear" type="0" value="100" />
            </struct>
        </element>
        <element name="PaletteID" type="0" value="54" />
        <element name="Comment" type="10" value="" />
    </struct>
</gff>
