<!-- This file was generated by the NWNTools GFF to XML writer.
     http://nwntools.sf.net/
     ** Do not hand edit unless you know what you are doing. **
 -->
<gff name="ats_book_bw_fl.uti" type="UTI " version="V3.2" >
    <struct id="-1" >
        <element name="TemplateResRef" type="11" value="ats_book_bw_fl" />
        <element name="BaseItem" type="5" value="74" />
        <element name="LocalizedName" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="Basics of Bowyering " />
        </element>
        <element name="Description" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="" />
        </element>
        <element name="DescIdentified" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" >
                <value><![CDATA[Basics of Bowyering 
--------------------------------


Bowyering is the noble art of the creation of the Bow.

Many different types of materials are capable of being used in bows, and Bowyers will have the opportunity to use all of them.

In addition, many types of hemp and cord may be used for the stringing of a bow, each with their own properties.

The basics of any bow, are a stave and a string.

However, in addition, the staves may be used in rough form, smoothed or planed.  Some of these processes may require additional tools to be used during the manufacture of the Bow.

It is also possible to assemble different tools within the bow, such as cams and followers, which can increase the attack rating of the bow.

To start your Bowyering career, purchase some Hemp Twine from your master Fletcher. Chop trees to get staves and combine them using the Bowyers Rack.  This will start you on your career to becoming a fine Bowyer.

There are 5 types of Bows available to craft.

ShortBows
LongBows
CrossBows
BattleBows
Specials

Short and Long and Cross Bows are conventional types.

BattleBows are useable by all but give stat increases in certain areas.

SpecialBows are generally either only craftable by a certain race, or useable by a certain class.]]></value>
            </localString>
        </element>
        <element name="Tag" type="10" value="ATS_BOOK_BW_FL" />
        <element name="Charges" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="Cost" type="4" value="50" />
        <element name="Stolen" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="StackSize" type="2" value="1" />
        <element name="Plot" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="AddCost" type="4" value="49" />
        <element name="Identified" type="0" value="1" />
        <element name="Cursed" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="ModelPart1" type="0" value="7" />
        <element name="PropertiesList" type="15" />
        <element name="PaletteID" type="0" value="60" />
        <element name="Comment" type="10" value="" />
    </struct>
</gff>
