<!-- This file was generated by the NWNTools GFF to XML writer.
     http://nwntools.sf.net/
     ** Do not hand edit unless you know what you are doing. **
 -->
<gff name="ats_book_gems1.uti" type="UTI " version="V3.2" >
    <struct id="-1" >
        <element name="TemplateResRef" type="11" value="ats_book_gems1" />
        <element name="BaseItem" type="5" value="74" />
        <element name="LocalizedName" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="Properties of Gems: Vol. 1" />
        </element>
        <element name="Description" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="This is a volume 1 of the Properties of Gems." />
        </element>
        <element name="DescIdentified" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" >
                <value><![CDATA[As you flip through the pages of this book, you see the properties of seven different types of gems.  How to capture these properties to cut, form, and polish.

Gems
--------------

*Malachite*
Malachite is a famous and very popular semi-precious stone. It is named for the green herb "mallow". Its banded light and dark green designs are one-of-a-kind, and give it a unique ornamental quality unlike that of any other stone.

Malachite, when cut properly, harnesses the power of Strength.
----------------------------------------------------------
*Amethyst*

Amethyst is the purple variety of quartz and is a popular gemstone. If it were not for its widespread availability, amethyst would be very expensive. The name "amethyst" means "not drunken." This was maybe due to a belief that amethyst would ward off the effects of alcohol, but most likely the name is referring to the almost wine-like color of some stones that they may have encountered. Its color is unparalleled, and even other, more expensive purple gemstones are often compared to its color and beauty. Although it must always be purple to be amethyst, it can and does have a wide range of purple shades. 

Amethyst, when cut properly, harnesses the power of Charisma.
----------------------------------------------------------
*Lapis Lazuli*

The ancient city of Ur has a thriving trade in lapis. The name is international, from the Latin, lapis, which means stone, and from the Arabic, azul, which means blue. Originally lapis was called ultramarinum, which means beyond the sea. Ground lapis was the secret of the blue in ultramarine, the pigment that painters use to paint the sea and the sky. Lapis is also popular in inlays.

Lapis Lazuli, when cut properly, harnesses the power of Dexterity.
----------------------------------------------------------
*Turquoise*

Turquoise is a valuable mineral and is possibly the most valuable, non-transparent mineral in the jewelry trade. It has been mined for eons. Its history also includes beautiful ornamental creations by Dwarves and Elves. Its popularity is still quite strong today.

Turquoise, when cut properly, harnesses the power of Constitution.
----------------------------------------------------------
*Opal*

In Precious Opal, the variety used most often in jewelry, there are many organized pockets of the spheres. These pockets contain spheres of approximately equal size and have a regular concentration, or structure, of the spheres. This has the effect of diffracting light at various wavelengths, creating colors. Each pocket produces a different color, with a different intensity depending on the angle from which a viewer sees it. The multicolored flashes of light that Opal emits gives it a truly beautiful and valuable look. 

Opal, when cut properly, harnesses the power of Wisdom and Save vs. Will but reduces the Strength of the wearer.  Due to it's natural properties, only Good and Neutral alignments can work and use this gem.
----------------------------------------------------------
*Onyx*

Onyx is the "Dark" sister of the Opal and can only be cut and used by Evil and Neutral aligned persons.

Onyx, when cut properly, harnesses the power of Dexerity and Save vs. Reflex but reduces the Strength of the wearer. 
----------------------------------------------------------
*Jade*

The toughness of jade is remarkable. It has a strength greater than steel and is sometimes put to work for axes, knives and weapons. Today, jade has become a symbolic stone used in ornaments and other religious artifacts. 

Jade, when cut properly, harnesses the power of Intelligence.
----------------------------------------------------------

Volume 2 contains recipes for the next set of gems.]]></value>
            </localString>
        </element>
        <element name="Tag" type="10" value="ATS_BOOK_GEMS1" />
        <element name="Charges" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="Cost" type="4" value="50" />
        <element name="Stolen" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="StackSize" type="2" value="1" />
        <element name="Plot" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="AddCost" type="4" value="49" />
        <element name="Identified" type="0" value="1" />
        <element name="Cursed" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="ModelPart1" type="0" value="3" />
        <element name="PropertiesList" type="15" />
        <element name="PaletteID" type="0" value="60" />
        <element name="Comment" type="10" value="" />
    </struct>
</gff>
