<!-- This file was generated by the NWNTools GFF to XML writer.
     http://nwntools.sf.net/
     ** Do not hand edit unless you know what you are doing. **
 -->
<gff name="ats_book_gems2.uti" type="UTI " version="V3.2" >
    <struct id="-1" >
        <element name="TemplateResRef" type="11" value="ats_book_gems2" />
        <element name="BaseItem" type="5" value="74" />
        <element name="LocalizedName" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="Properties of Gems: Vol. 2" />
        </element>
        <element name="Description" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="This is a volume 2 of Properties of Gems" />
        </element>
        <element name="DescIdentified" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" >
                <value><![CDATA[As you flip through the pages of this book, you see the properties of seven different types of gems.  How to capture these properties to cut, form, and polish.

Gems
--------------

*Pearl*

Pearls are an organic gem, created when an oyster covers a foreign object with beautiful layers of nacre. These organic gems can be found in ancient rock near oceans or within living oysters.

Pearl, when cut properly, harnesses the power of Wisdom.
----------------------------------------------------------
*Sapphire/Black Sapphire*

The Sapphires are the second hardest natural mineral known.  The Black variety of Sapphire is more rare than the blue variety.

Sapphire, when cut properly, enhances the power of Wisdom, Save vs. Negative Energy, but cuts the Constitution of the bearer.  Due to it's natural properties, only Good aligned characters can cut and wear this gem.

Black Sapphire, when cut properly, enhances the power of Dexterity, Save vs. Positive Energy, but reduces the Charisma of the bearer.  Due to it's natural properties, only Evil aligned characters can cut and wear this gem.
----------------------------------------------------------
*Fire Opal*

Fire opal breaks all the rules for opal. Opal is a gem valued for its play of color, the shifting light showing through from its depths. Body color is only a backdrop for the main attraction. But the color of fire opal is hard to ignore: hot yellows, oranges, and reds so bright they look as though they might glow in the dark. 

Fire Opal, when cut properly, enhances the power of Charisma, Save vs. Fortitude, but reduces the Dexterity of the bearer.
----------------------------------------------------------
*Ruby*

Which colour would you spontaneously associate with love and vividness, passion and power? Obviously this will evoke the colour red. Red symbolizes love, it emanates warmth and a strong sense of life. Red is also the colour of Ruby, the King of gemstones. After all, in the fascinating realm of gemstones rubies are the generally accepted emperors.  Ruby is the red sister of the Sapphire.

Ruby, when cut properly, enhances the power of Constitution and Save vs. Mind.
----------------------------------------------------------
*Emerald*

Emeralds are fascinating gemstones. They show the most beautiful, deepest and most brilliant green imaginable: Emerald green. Inclusions are allowed, and nevertheless, in top qualities fine Emerald are even more valuable than diamonds.

Emerald, when cut properly, enhances the power of Dexterity and Save vs. Fear.
----------------------------------------------------------
*Diamond*

Diamond is the ultimate gemstone, having few weaknesses and many strengths. It is well known that Diamond is the hardest substance found in nature.
As a gemstone, Diamond's single flaw (perfect cleavage) is far outdistanced by the sum of its positive qualities. It has a broad color range, high refraction, high dispersion or fire, very low reactivity to chemicals, rarity, and of course, extreme hardness and durability. 
A skilled diamond setter and/or jeweler will prevent any of this single flaw from being in a position to be struck while mounted in a jewelry piece. 
----------------------------------------------------------

Volume 1 contains recipes for the previous set of gems.]]></value>
            </localString>
        </element>
        <element name="Tag" type="10" value="ATS_BOOK_GEMS2" />
        <element name="Charges" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="Cost" type="4" value="100" />
        <element name="Stolen" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="StackSize" type="2" value="1" />
        <element name="Plot" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="AddCost" type="4" value="99" />
        <element name="Identified" type="0" value="1" />
        <element name="Cursed" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="ModelPart1" type="0" value="5" />
        <element name="PropertiesList" type="15" />
        <element name="PaletteID" type="0" value="60" />
        <element name="Comment" type="10" value="" />
    </struct>
</gff>
