<!-- This file was generated by the NWNTools GFF to XML writer.
     http://nwntools.sf.net/
     ** Do not hand edit unless you know what you are doing. **
 -->
<gff name="ats_book_tanning.uti" type="UTI " version="V3.2" >
    <struct id="-1" >
        <element name="TemplateResRef" type="11" value="ats_book_tanning" />
        <element name="BaseItem" type="5" value="74" />
        <element name="LocalizedName" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="Basics of Tanning" />
        </element>
        <element name="Description" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="" />
        </element>
        <element name="DescIdentified" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" >
                <value><![CDATA[(This is placeholder text for more detailed tanning instructions)

To begin tanning, you must first purchase a skinning knife to get pelts from various animals such as badgers, deer, bears, and cougars.  After the animal is dead, with the knife equipped, just click on the corpse.  You should get some pelts and meat.  Now find the closet Smoker Oven so you can begin the process of tanning leather.

The first is curing the pelts.  You will always need Tanning Salt, an Oak Log, and the pelt you are going to cure.  When you have these, click on the smoker oven and choose to cure the apporiate pelt.  If you suceed you will get cured leather.  If you fail, you might get ruined leather which can be resold or saved for other uses later.  Different types of pelt produce different sizes of leather hides but they also require different amounts of salt and wood.

Now thjat you have some cured leather, you can tan this to produce tanned leather by clicking on a Water Basin.  This will give you the option to tan hides. You will need some tannic acid and more tanning salts to do this.

After tanning, you can also harden leather if you desire.  This can also be done at the Water Basin by having beeswax, tanning oils, and the tanned leather you want to harden.

Now that you have your various hides, you can sell them to players or use them yourself in other tradeskills.

]]></value>
            </localString>
        </element>
        <element name="Tag" type="10" value="ATS_BOOK_TANNING" />
        <element name="Charges" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="Cost" type="4" value="1" />
        <element name="Stolen" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="StackSize" type="2" value="1" />
        <element name="Plot" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="AddCost" type="4" value="0" />
        <element name="Identified" type="0" value="1" />
        <element name="Cursed" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="ModelPart1" type="0" value="6" />
        <element name="PropertiesList" type="15" />
        <element name="PaletteID" type="0" value="60" />
        <element name="Comment" type="10" value="" />
    </struct>
</gff>
