<!-- This file was generated by the NWNTools GFF to XML writer.
     http://nwntools.sf.net/
     ** Do not hand edit unless you know what you are doing. **
 -->
<gff name="ats_book_smith1.uti" type="UTI " version="V3.2" >
    <struct id="-1" >
        <element name="TemplateResRef" type="11" value="ats_book_smith1" />
        <element name="BaseItem" type="5" value="74" />
        <element name="LocalizedName" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="Apprentice&apos;s Guide to Blacksmithing" />
        </element>
        <element name="Description" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="" />
        </element>
        <element name="DescIdentified" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" >
                <value><![CDATA[Basics of Blacksmithing

     So you want to be a blacksmith?  You must first start by being an
     apprentice.  After reading these pages, you will be on your way to be
     making a variety of different armors and weapons.  This book is divided in
     four sections.  The first will teach you about smelting ore into ingots.
     Then next section deals with how to use the anvil and crafting.  The third
     section deals with  skills and skill gain.  And finally, the last section
     will introduce more advanced topics such as salvaging crafted items.

    SECTION 1
    ----------

    Smelting Ore
         The main component of all blacksmithing recipes is the ingot, and the
         first duty of any blacksmith is to be able to make ingots.  There are
         12 different types of ingots which can be smelted from 12 different types
         of ore.  These include: copper, tinstone, iron, silver, gold, shadow iron,
         verdicite, rubicite, syenite, mithral, adamantine, and myrkandite.  
         With each material type, there is an increasing difficulty both to smelt 
         and to use for crafts.  Smelting will directly use your blacksmithing skill 
         in determining both success and the amount of useable ingots you produce 
         from an ore.

         To smelt ore, first click on the forge located in most blacksmithing
         shops. This will bring up the forge's inventory display.  Place any
         amount of ore into the forge's inventory and click "close".
         A dialogue menu will then display showing your available options.
         You can choose to immediately smelt the ore or influence your chances
         of producing ore by fanning the flames.

         There are three different levels of flame intensity.  The biggest flame
         will make the ore easier to smelt but will produce less ingots, while
         the smallest flame makes it more difficult to smelt ore, it produces
         the most ingots.  The medium flame is somewhere in the middle.  It's
         usually advisable to start with the biggest flame first when working
         with a new material type.  As your skills improve, you can lower the
         intensity of the flame.  When you are satisfied with your choice,
         select the smelt ore option and if you are skilled enough and lucky,
         you will have produced some useable ingots!

    Section 2
    ----------

    The Anvil
         The most important tool of any blacksmith is the anvil.  Now that you
         have some useable ingots, it is time to begin making some basic items.
         In order to use the anvil, you must have a smithing hammer equipped.
         Smithing hammers come in a variety of different material types and can
         be purchased from merchants or can be made through weaponcrafting.
         You will need to have the appropriate weapon proficiency in martial
         weapons, however, to equip the smithing hammer. Like all trade tools,
         smithing hammers degrade over time with use. Each material type offers
         different levels of durability.

         With your smithing hammer equipped, click on the anvil to begin
         crafting. You will see a dialogue menu come up with options to either
         craft armors or craft weapons.  Crafting armors and crafting weapons
         each use different skills.  If you want to focus on armors, select
         armor and you will see a list of different armor pieces such as body,
         head, shields, or misc. You can also experiment with  weapons.   If you
         have very little or no skill, you will have to start small.  Select the
         Misc category under armor and you should see an option in red for
         Iron Studs.  This is one of your most basic armor craftable items.
         Iron studs are used mainly in leathercrafting so although you may not
         have use for them, they can offer some easy training and can earn you
         money by selling them to other players who do need them.

         Now select the iron studs option.  You should begin to craft.  It takes
         time to craft an item.  Crafting iron studs take one iron ingot.  Make
         sure you have an iron ingot in your inventory.  If you succeed, the
         components will automatically be used up and you will get the newly
         crafted item in your inventory.  If you fail, there is a chance you
         will lose some of your components.

         If you noticed, the text for Iron Studs was in Red.  Depending on your
         skill level and the difficulty to make a certain item, the text for
         item names will appear in different colors.  Red means that the item is
         very difficult to make for your skill level. Dark blue means you still
         need some practice.  Light blue means the item is  reasonably easy to
         make.  Green means the item is trivial to make and you will usually
         succeed but not learn from the success.  Any items that you do not have
         enough skill to make, will not display until you reach a minimum level
         and then it will display as red to begin with.  Practice, practice,
         practice and some day you will see most items are green and trivial to
         you.

    Section 3
    ----------

    The Skills
         Blacksmithing mainly encompasses three skills.  The first is just
         Blacksmithing.  Blacksmithing is a secondary skill.  Secondary skills
         are skills which other skills rely on and are not as difficult to
         master. Blacksmithing is used to directly determine your success in
         smelting ore and the amount of ingots you produce.  It is also used to
         directly determine how successful you are in salvaging crafted items.
         And finally it determines how likely you to make an exceptional piece
         of armor or weapon. Exceptionally crafted items usually have better
         traits and sell for slightly more.  The next two skills are
         Armorcrafting and Weaponcrafting.

         These are primary skills and are usually more difficult to master.
         Armorcrafting directly influences what types of armor you can make,
         what materials you can work with when making them, and your success
         rates.

         Weaponcrafting does the same but for weapons and tools.

    Skill Gain
         Your skills will go up over time and with continued use.  It takes a
         lot of practice and patience to become a master blacksmith.  When you
         succeed in making an item, there is a chance your skill will increase.
         The harder the item was to make, the more likely you will see skill
         gain. There is a point, however, when an items becomes trivial to make.
         You will then no longer gain any skill from making this item and should
         move on to harder items or more difficult materials.  Even if you fail
         making a difficult item, there is a small chance you will gain skill.
         If you make an exceptional item, there is also a chance for your
         Blacksmithing skill to increase as well.

    Section 4
    ---------

    Advanced Topics
          Now that you have mastered the basics of blacksmithing, there are a
          few extra things you should now about. Blacksmithing is not all about
          just crafting basic items from different material types.  There are
          also several important things a blacksmith can do as he becomes a
          master.

    Salvaging Crafted Items
         If you find that you are losing money by selling your crafted items
         back to a merchant, you also have the option to salvage your crafted
         items.  By salvaging them, you will gain back some of the ingots needed
         to make the item.  To salvage an armor or weapon, simply click on the
         forge and place the item in the forge's inventory and close it.  You
         will see an option to salvage crafted armor or weapons.  Select this
         and depending on you Blacksmithing skill level, you will either succeed
         in which case you will gain back some of the ingots used to make the
         item or you will fail and the item will be consumed.  Failing to
         salvage an item is rare even for a beginning blacksmith.  Usually with
         little skill, you just produce less ingots from the item.  Salvaging is
         a good way to increase your skills.

    Jeweled Armor and Weapons
         More on this topic to come.

    Imbued Armor and Weapons
         More on this topic to come.
]]></value>
            </localString>
        </element>
        <element name="Tag" type="10" value="ATS_BOOK_SMITH1" />
        <element name="Charges" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="Cost" type="4" value="1" />
        <element name="Stolen" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="StackSize" type="2" value="1" />
        <element name="Plot" type="0" value="1" />
        <element name="AddCost" type="4" value="0" />
        <element name="Identified" type="0" value="1" />
        <element name="Cursed" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="ModelPart1" type="0" value="1" />
        <element name="PropertiesList" type="15" />
        <element name="PaletteID" type="0" value="60" />
        <element name="Comment" type="10" value="" />
    </struct>
</gff>
