<!-- This file was generated by the NWNTools GFF to XML writer.
     http://nwntools.sf.net/
     ** Do not hand edit unless you know what you are doing. **
 -->
<gff name="ats_book_gc_jc.uti" type="UTI " version="V3.2" >
    <struct id="-1" >
        <element name="TemplateResRef" type="11" value="ats_book_gc_jc" />
        <element name="BaseItem" type="5" value="74" />
        <element name="LocalizedName" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="Basics of Gemcutting and Jewelcrafting" />
        </element>
        <element name="Description" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" value="" />
        </element>
        <element name="DescIdentified" type="12" value="-1" >
            <localString languageId="0" >
                <value><![CDATA[Basics of Gemcutting and Jewelcrafting
---------------------------------------

     So you want to be a Gemcutter or Jewelcrafter?  You must first start by being an apprentice.  After reading these pages, you will be on your way to be cutting a variety of different gems and jewelry.  This book is divided in four sections.  The first will teach you about cutting Rough Gems into Cut Gems.  Then next section deals with how to Craft Jewelry using these Cut Gems.  The third section deals with skills and skill gain.  
     
     The books, Properties of Gems: Volumes 1 and 2, discuss the various properties of gems.  And Properties of Metals: Volumes 1 and 2, discuss the various properties of metal ignots.
     
     It must be said that a person can be a Gemcutter and/or a Jewelcrafter.  These are two separate tradeskills to master.

SECTION 1
-------------------

Cutting Gems

     The main component of all Jewelcrafting recipes are Cut Gems.  Cut Gems are the realm of Gemcutters.  There are 14 different types of rough gems; Malachite, Amethyst, Lapis Lazuli, Turquoise, Opal, Onyx, Jade, Pearl, Sapphire, Black Sapphire, Fire Opal, Ruby, Emerald, and Diamond.
     
     With each material type,  there is an increasing difficulty both to cut and to use for crafts.  Cutting gems will directly use your gemcutting skill in determining both success and the quality of Cut Gems from Rough Gems.  The lesser Gems (Malachite, Amethyst, Lapis Lazuli, and Turquoise) can be store bought and used to create Cut Gems.
     
     To cut gems, first click on the chisel located in your inventory.  This will bring up the chisel's dialogue menu showing your available options.  Choose which Cut Gem you would like to attempt to produce and, with some luck and skill, voila! you will have created a Cut Gem!
     
     
Section 2
----------------

The Jewelcrafting Desk

     The most important tool of any Jewelcrafter is the Jewelcrafting Desk.  Once you have some useable Cut Gems, it is time to begin making some basic items.  
     
     Not only do you need a Cut Gem to craft a piece of jewelry, you also need two ingots of the appropriate metal for a ring and three ingots for an amulet.  Ingots can be made using the Smithing tradeskill or bought from your local PC Smith.
     
     In addition to two or three Ingots, all jewelcrafting recipes require a mold.  A Smooth Ring recipe requires a smooth ring mold, a Smooth Amulet recipe requires a smooth amulet mold, and so on.
     
     Finally, you will need to equip a Gemsetter.
     
     Click on the Jewelcrafting Desk to begin crafting.  You will see a dialogue menu come up with options of the various types of jewelry that can be made (Smooth Ring, Smooth Amulet, etc.)  The next level in the menu will be the names of recipes that you can make and the final level will be the names of the various gems that you have skill to add to that recipe.  
     
     For example, if you have very little or no skill, you will have to start small.   Look into the menu and you should see an option for Smooth Amulet, Select it.  Then the next level will be for "Smooth Copper Amulet", Select it.  Finally there should be an item in red for Malachite.  Malachite is one of your most basic gems used to craft rings and amulets.  Select it.  You should begin to craft.  It takes time to craft an item.  
     
     To recap, in order to make a Copper Malachite Amulet, you will need a Cut Malachite Gem, an amulet mold and three ingots of copper.
     
     If you succeed, the components will automatically be used up and you will get the newly crafted item in your inventory.  If you fail, there is a chance you will lose some of your components. 
     
     If you noticed, the text for Malachite was in Red.  Depending on your skill level and the difficulty to make a certain item, the text for item names will appear in different colors.  Red means that the item is very difficult to make for your skill level. Dark blue means you still need some practice.  Light blue means the item is  reasonably easy to make.  Green means the item is trivial to make and you will usually succeed but not learn from the success.  Any items that you do not have enough skill to make, will not display until you reach a minimum level and then it will display as red to begin with.  Practice, practice, practice and some day you will see most items are green and trivial to you.  

Section 3
----------------

The Skills

     Jewelcrafting and Gemcutting are two skills that depend upon one another.  The primary skill is Jewelcrafting and the secondary skill is Gemcutting.  Secondary skills are skills which other skills rely on and are not as difficult to master.  Gemcutting skill is used to directly determine your success in cutting gems and the quality of the cut gems you produce.  It is also used to directly determine how successful you are in salvaging crafted items. And finally it determines how likely you to make an exceptional piece of armor or weapon.  Exceptionally crafted items usually have better traits and sell for slightly more.  The primary skill is Jewelcrafting.  This primary skill is usually more difficult to master than the secondary skill Gemcutting.  Jewelcrafting directly influences what types of rings and amulets you can craft, what materials you can work with when crafting them, and your success rates. 

Skill Gain

     Your skills will go up over time and with continued use.  It takes a lot of practice and patience to become a Master Gemcutter or Jewelcrafter.  When you succeed in making an item, there is a chance your skill will increase.  The harder the item was to make, the more likely you will see skill gain.  There is a point, however, when an items becomes trivial to make.  You will then no longer gain any skill from making this item and should move on to harder items or more difficult materials.  Even if you fail making a difficult item, there is a small chance you will gain skill.
     ]]></value>
            </localString>
        </element>
        <element name="Tag" type="10" value="ATS_BOOK_GC_JC" />
        <element name="Charges" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="Cost" type="4" value="50" />
        <element name="Stolen" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="StackSize" type="2" value="1" />
        <element name="Plot" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="AddCost" type="4" value="49" />
        <element name="Identified" type="0" value="1" />
        <element name="Cursed" type="0" value="0" />
        <element name="ModelPart1" type="0" value="5" />
        <element name="PropertiesList" type="15" />
        <element name="PaletteID" type="0" value="60" />
        <element name="Comment" type="10" value="" />
    </struct>
</gff>
